Finding Aid for the Minasian Collection of Near Eastern Manuscripts LSC.1147
UCLA Library Special Collections
Minasian collection of Near Eastern Manuscripts
circa 1100-1899
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.1147
88.6 linear feet (178 boxes)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
PORTIONS OF THIS COLLECTION HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. See the Online Items Available note for the link to the digitized materials.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9922214963606533
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Caro O. Minasian, 1968.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of Arabic, Persian, Turkish, and Urdu manuscripts relating to Persian and Arabic lexicography, Persian literature, history, Shiite theology and jurisprudence, practical arts, and philosophy and logic.
Related Material
Collection of Persian Calligraphic Samples (Collection 1123). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Caro Minasian Collection (Collection 1632). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Exhibit Collection of Near Eastern Manuscripts, 1492-1848(6 items).
manuscripts (documents) -- Arab countries.
- 1-3. (Box 1)
- 4-8. (Box 2)
- 9-24. (Box 3)
- 25-28. (Box 4)
- 29-35. (Box 5)
- 36-42. (Box 6)
- 43-48. (Box 7)
- 49-50. (Box 8)
- 51-53. (Box 9)
- 54-56. (Box 10)
- 57-61. (Box 11)
  General note
  (no.61 also on positive microfilm in box)
- 62-66. (Box 12)
- 67. (Box 13)
- 68-72. (Box 14)
- 73-79. (Box 15)
- 80-83. (Box 16)
- 84-94. (Box 17)
- 95-103. (Box 18)
- 104-117. (Box 19)
- 118-122. (Box 20)
- 123-128. (Box 21)
- 129-136. (Box 22)
- 137-147. (Box 23)
- 148-149. (Box 24)
- 150-158, 160-160a. (Box 25)
- 161-168. (Box 26)
- 169-174. (Box 27)
- 175-178. (Box 28)
- 179-188. (Box 29)
- 189-197. (Box 30)
- 198-208. (Box 31)
- 209-222. (Box 32)
- 223-225. (Box 33)
- 226-229. (Box 34)
- 230-234. (Box 35)
- 235-238. (Box 36)
- 239-241. (Box 37)
- 242. (Box 38)
- 243-244. (Box 39)
- 245-249. (Box 40)
- 250-254. (Box 41)
- 255-263. (Box 42)
- 264-277. (Box 43)
- 278-284. (Box 44)
- 285-302. (Box 45)
- 303-314. (Box 46)
- 315-321. (Box 47)
- 322-334. (Box 48)
- 335-346. (Box 49)
- 347-354. (Box 50)
- 347-354. (Box 51)
- 358-366. (Box 52)
- 367-375. (Box 53)
- 376-383. (Box 54)
- 384-407. (Box 55)
- 408-419. (Box 56)
- 420-422. (Box 57)
- 423-431. (Box 58)
- 432-445. (Box 59)
- 446-448. (Box 60)
- 449-452. (Box 61)
- 453-455. (Box 62)
- 456-464. (Box 63)
- 465-467. (Box 64)
- 468-477. (Box 65)
- 478-487. (Box 66)
- 488-490. (Box 67)
- 491-492. (Box 68)
- 493-495. (Box 69)
- 496-499. (Box 70)
- 500-508. (Box 71)
- 509-521. (Box 72)
- 522-531. (Box 73)
- 532-534. (Box 74)
- 535-549. (Box 75)
- 550-562. (Box 76)
- 563-577. (Box 77)
- 578-580. (Box 78)
- 581-597. (Box 79)
- 598-613. (Box 80)
- 614-633. (Box 81)
- 634-641. (Box 82)
- 642-650. (Box 83)
- 651-655. (Box 84)
- 656-665. (Box 85)
- 666-674. (Box 86)
- 675-679. (Box 87)
- 680-688. (Box 88)
- 689-693. (Box 89)
- 694-701. (Box 90)
- 702-704. (Box 91)
- 705-711. (Box 92)
- 712-720. (Box 93)
- 721-725. (Box 94)
- 726-731. (Box 95)
- 732-735. (Box 96)
- 736-747. (Box 97)
- 748-750. (Box 98)
- 751-759. (Box 99)
- 760-765. (Box 100)
- 766-775. (Box 101)
- 776-783. (Box 102)
- 784-787. (Box 103)
- 788-796. (Box 104)
- 797-799. (Box 105)
- 800-803. (Box 106)
- 804-808. (Box 107)
- 809-822. (Box 108)
- 823-826. (Box 109)
- 827-835. (Box 110)
- 836-847. (Box 111)
- 848-860. (Box 112)
- 861-872. (Box 113)
- 873-877. (Box 114)
- 878-890. (Box 115)
- 891-904. (Box 116)
- 905-921. (Box 117)
- 922-924. (Box 118)
- 925-936. (Box 119)
- 937-950. (Box 120)
- 951-960. (Box 121)
- 967-977. (Box 122)
- 978-986. (Box 123)
- 987-1000. (Box 124)
- 1001-1011. (Box 125)
- 1012-1025. (Box 126)
- 1026-1032. (Box 127)
- 1033-1035. (Box 128)
- 1036-1039. (Box 129)
- 1040-1049. (Box 130)
- 1050-1061. (Box 131)
- 1062-1065. (Box 132)
- 1066-1068. (Box 133)
- 1069-1079. (Box 134)
- 1080-1097. (Box 135)
- 1098-1100. (Box 136)
- 1101-1110. (Box 137)
- 1111-1123. (Box 138)
- 1124-1132. (Box 139)
- 1133-1138. (Box 140)
- 1139-1144. (Box 141)
- 1145-1154. (Box 142)
- 1155-1157. (Box 143)
- 1158-1170. (Box 144)
- 1171-1185. (Box 145)
- 1186-1196. (Box 146)
- 1197-1200. (Box 147)
- 1201-1208. (Box 148)
- 1209-1220. (Box 149)
- 1221-1238. (Box 150)
- 1239-1243. (Box 151)
- 1244-1249. (Box 152)
- 1250-1258. (Box 153)
- 1259-1276. (Box 154)
- 1277-1285. (Box 155)
- 1286-1301. (Box 156)
- 1302-1316. (Box 157)
- 1317-1319. (Box 158)
- 1320-1330. (Box 159)
- 1331-1344. (Box 160)
- 1345-1351. (Box 161)
- 1352-1368. (Box 162)
- 1369-1372. (Box 163)
- 1373-1384. (Box 164)
- 1385-1391. (Box 165)
- 1392-1398. (Box 166)
- 1399-1406. (Box 167)
- 1407-1419. (Box 168)
- 1420-1439. (Box 169)
- 1440-1454. (Box 170)
- 1455-1475. (Box 171)
- 1476-1496. (Box 172)
- 1497-1504. (Box 173)
- 1505-1506. (Box 174)
- 1508-1524. (Box 175)
- 1529-1530, Koran. (Box 176)
- 1531, unmarked, and folios from various manuscripts. (Box 177)
- Persian Poetry, examples of calligraphy, and manuscripts (Box 178)